import { IQuestion } from "./generateQuestions";

export default <Array<IQuestion>>[
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question: '______ Turkish Airlines is one of _______ safest airlines in ______ world.',
    options: ['- / the / the', 'the / the / -', '- / - / the', 'the / - / the'],
    correctAnswer: '- / the / the',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question: 'My parents never let me _____________ out at nights.',
    options: ['go', 'gone', 'to go', 'going'],
    correctAnswer: 'go',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question:
      'The young woman stopped to imagine the distance between her and her family, now that she was in France and thought: 6000 miles ______ a long distance, yet sometimes not far enough.',
    options: ['are', 'does', 'were', 'is'],
    correctAnswer: 'is',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question: 'Pete __________ by the time the meeting starts.',
    options: ['arrived', 'will have arrived', 'had arrived', 'has arrived'],
    correctAnswer: 'will have arrived',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question: 'While he _____________ his speech, the minister suddenly ___________ a sharp pain in his left arm.',
    options: ['made / felt', 'was making / feel', 'made / was feeling', 'was making / felt'],
    correctAnswer: 'was making / felt',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question: 'Never before _______________ such ridiculous arguments.',
    options: ['we had heard', 'have we heard', 'we have heard', 'we could have heard'],
    correctAnswer: 'have we heard',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question: '__________ you have driven a car like this, you will never want to drive any other car.',
    options: ['Although', 'Once', 'In case', 'Therefore'],
    correctAnswer: 'Once',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question: 'The roads seem to be _______________ icy so drive carefully.',
    options: ['have getting', 'got', 'getting', 'to get'],
    correctAnswer: 'getting',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question: 'The council is in discussion with Donald Trump, ________________ land most of the village is built.',
    options: ['of which', 'that', 'who', 'on whose'],
    correctAnswer: 'on whose',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question: 'The boss wanted to know _________.',
    options: ['why we were late', 'why were you late', 'why have you been late', 'why are we late'],
    correctAnswer: 'why we were late',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question:
      'Frida Kahlo, Mexico’s best known woman painter, ______ polio at the age of six and ________ to her bed for nine months.',
    options: ['get / confined', 'got / was confined', 'was getting / being confined', 'got / had been confined'],
    correctAnswer: 'got / was confined',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question:
      'The Austrian monk, Gregori Mendel, developed the fundamental principles that _________ the modern science of genetics.',
    options: ['will have become', 'had become', 'would become', 'was becoming'],
    correctAnswer: 'would become',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question: 'Inflation in Turkey is believed ______________ by strict measures ___________ by the government.',
    options: [
      'to be pulled down / taking',
      'to pull down / are taken',
      'to be pulling down / taken',
      'to have been pulled down / taken',
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'to have been pulled down / taken',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question: 'The film is unusual ______________ it features only four actors.',
    options: ['accordingly', 'due to', 'in that', 'because of'],
    correctAnswer: 'in that',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question: 'If the talks _________________, it would be a disadvantage for us.',
    options: ['would stopped', 'were to stop', 'they to stop', 'would stop'],
    correctAnswer: 'were to stop',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question: 'Could you tell me __________ ?',
    options: ['what did Ann buy', 'why was Jack late to class', 'what time the plane arrives', 'who is that man'],
    correctAnswer: 'what time the plane arrives',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question: 'I wish I ____________ more time to discuss this matter with you.',
    options: ['have', 'had', 'am having', 'will have'],
    correctAnswer: 'had',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question: 'You ______________ drive so fast. The play doesn’t start until nine o’clock.',
    options: ['needn’t to', 'haven’t to', 'don’t need', 'don’t have to'],
    correctAnswer: 'don’t have to',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question: 'My brother is ____________ cleverer than me.',
    options: ['far', 'almost', 'nearly', 'more'],
    correctAnswer: 'far',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question:
      'When you arrive at London Airport you ______________ by our representative who will accompany you to your hotel.',
    options: ['are meeting', 'are going to meet', 'will have met', 'will be met'],
    correctAnswer: 'will be met',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question: 'You will come to my birthday party, __________ ?',
    options: ['would you', 'will you', "won't you", "wouldn't you"],
    correctAnswer: "won't you",
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question: 'The Minister for Trade and Industry is ______________ of the situation as the union leaders.',
    options: ['more than just a prisoner', 'just as much a prisoner', 'just as prisoner', 'just a prisoner as'],
    correctAnswer: 'just as much a prisoner',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question: 'There is no chance _______________ a cure if we don’t fund more research.',
    options: ['to find', 'to be found', 'of find', 'of finding'],
    correctAnswer: 'of finding',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question:
      'Oil based house paints are __________ easy to work with ___________ quick to clean, but they are often preferred to latex paints.',
    options: ['not only / but also', 'both / or', 'neither / nor', 'either / or'],
    correctAnswer: 'neither / nor',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question:
      'The two cars my father owns are very old ______________ are in very good condition and excellent working order.',
    options: ['both of they', 'and both of them', 'so both', 'but both of them'],
    correctAnswer: 'but both of them',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question: 'Before _____________ the town, I think you should talk to your mother.',
    options: ['to leave', 'leaving', 'to leaving', 'having leaving'],
    correctAnswer: 'leaving',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question: 'It was _____________ waiting list that we couldn’t possibly get a flight.',
    options: ['such a long', 'too long', 'enough long', 'so long'],
    correctAnswer: 'such a long',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question: 'She looked at me ___________ amazement when she saw me.',
    options: ['at', 'in', 'of', 'very'],
    correctAnswer: 'in',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question: 'If you had told me that he never pays his debts, I _____________ him any money.',
    options: ['won’t lend', 'wouldn’t lend', " didn't lend", "wouldn't have lent"],
    correctAnswer: "wouldn't have lent",
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question:
      'I’d appreciate it if you let me know in advance whether or not you ___________ to North Cyprus next summer.',
    options: ['will or won’t come', 'will be coming', 'going to come', 'will have come'],
    correctAnswer: 'will be coming',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question:
      'I don’t remember __________ of the decision to change the company policy on vacations. When was it decided?',
    options: ['telling', 'to be told', 'to tell', 'being told'],
    correctAnswer: 'being told',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question: '__________ he wasn’t hungry, he ate everything put in front of him.',
    options: ['In spite', 'Unless', 'Even', 'Although'],
    correctAnswer: 'Although',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question:
      'Ali’s father _________ to work for an estate agent before they moved to Cyprus, but I don’t know what he does now.',
    options: ['was used', 'used', 'got used', 'use'],
    correctAnswer: 'used',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question: 'He is a slow reader because he looks ___________ every word in his dictionary.',
    options: ['to', 'in', 'up', 'at'],
    correctAnswer: 'up',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question: 'Where did you live before you ____________ married?',
    options: ['got', 'made', 'did', 'became'],
    correctAnswer: 'got',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question: 'My car broke ________ on the way here , so I was half an hour late for my appointment.',
    options: ['in', 'down', 'out', 'through'],
    correctAnswer: 'down',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question: 'I’m going to put _________ all my housework until my exams are over.',
    options: ['out', 'on', 'in', 'off'],
    correctAnswer: 'off',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question: 'I will be with you ___________.',
    options: ['justly', 'directly', 'highly', 'widely'],
    correctAnswer: 'directly',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question: 'No sooner had I arrived in Ankara ____________ I was told to go back to Adana.',
    options: ['that', 'which', 'than', 'when'],
    correctAnswer: 'than',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question: 'Unable to remember _______________, he walked all around the neighborhood looking for his car.',
    options: ['where he was parking', 'where he has parked', 'where to park', 'where he had parked'],
    correctAnswer: 'where he had parked',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question: 'Not once _____________ at home when I phoned.',
    options: ['she was', 'she would be', 'did she', 'was she'],
    correctAnswer: 'was she',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question: 'Shortly after my father started his own business, our life style changed __________ .',
    options: ['drastically', 'eventually', 'reluctantly', 'desperately'],
    correctAnswer: 'drastically',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question:
      'My parents are looking forward to Mercan Dede’s concert. They are going to be very ________ when I tell them that it’s been cancelled.',
    options: ['disapproving', 'exciting', 'disinterested', 'disappointed'],
    correctAnswer: 'disappointed',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question: 'It has been, _____________ 1984, the hottest July for the last 100 years.',
    options: ['excepted', 'besides', 'obviously', 'except for'],
    correctAnswer: 'except for',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question: 'We wrote to them last week and ____________ them to reply in the next few days.',
    options: ['believe', 'hope', 'expect', 'look forward to'],
    correctAnswer: 'expect',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question:
      'We don’t usually deal with cases like that in this office. I’ll have to _______ you to our Claims Department.',
    options: ['recommend', 'refer', 'regard', 'remind'],
    correctAnswer: 'refer',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question: 'Could you _____________ me to pay the telephone bill? It will be disconnected if we don’t.',
    options: ['remember', 'require', 'refresh', 'remind'],
    correctAnswer: 'remind',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question: 'This letter must be typed ___________ because it has to be mailed before lunch time.',
    options: ['spectacularly', 'immediately', 'unexpectedly', 'critically'],
    correctAnswer: 'immediately',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question:
      'One of the _______ for starting immediately in an engineering department in this university is scoring over 70 on the Proficiency Exam.',
    options: ['objections', 'objection', 'requirements', 'requirement'],
    correctAnswer: 'requirements',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question:
      'Mark’s remarks were quite ____________ at the meeting yesterday. The boss is thinking very seriously about firing him.',
    options: ['offensive', 'adequate', 'genuine', 'mature'],
    correctAnswer: 'offensive',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'beginner',
    instructions: 'Choose the correct answer',
    question:
      'The storm was __________________. No one was prepared for it so some people couldn’t escape and got injured.',
    options: ['irrelevant', 'unexpected', 'impossible', 'illegal'],
    correctAnswer: 'unexpected',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'intermediate',
    instructions: 'Choose the word or phrase which is closest in meaning to the one underlined.',
    question:
      'Medical experts have viewed high doses of vitamins as a popular remedy whose value is, as yet, <u>unproven.</u>',
    options: ['unintentional', 'unfounded', 'prescribed', 'beneficial'],
    correctAnswer: 'unfounded',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'intermediate',
    instructions: 'Choose the word or phrase which is closest in meaning to the one underlined.',
    question:
      'Because of her <u>conservative</u> views, the professor never accepts anything not related to traditional values and the status quo.',
    options: ['conventional', 'progressive', 'modern', 'economic'],
    correctAnswer: 'conventional',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'intermediate',
    instructions: 'Choose the word or phrase which is closest in meaning to the one underlined.',
    question:
      'One of the most challenging part of being a student that lives away from home is <u>putting up with</u> poor quality housing or unfriendly roommates.',
    options: ['taking care of', 'saving', 'bearing', 'looking up'],
    correctAnswer: 'bearing',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'intermediate',
    instructions: 'Choose the word or phrase which is closest in meaning to the one underlined.',
    question:
      'The candidate answered tough questions with disarming sincerity, winning over many viewers who had previously supported her rival.',
    options: ['presumptuous', 'rude', 'fighting', 'conciliatory'],
    correctAnswer: 'conciliatory',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'intermediate',
    instructions: 'Choose the word or phrase which is closest in meaning to the one underlined.',
    question: 'The new law is expected to <u>curb</u> the number of illegal immigrants entering the country.',
    options: ['increase', 'decrease', 'stop', 'encourage'],
    correctAnswer: 'decrease',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'intermediate',
    instructions: 'Choose the word or phrase which is closest in meaning to the one underlined.',
    question:
      'It is important to <u>take into account</u> the fact that the company is in financial trouble before making any decisions.',
    options: ['consider', 'ignore', 'understand', 'remember'],
    correctAnswer: 'consider',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'intermediate',
    instructions: 'Choose the word or phrase which is closest in meaning to the one underlined.',
    question: 'Whereas the first part of the book was interesting, the <u>latter</u> part was quite boring.',
    options: ['first', 'last', 'middle', 'earlier'],
    correctAnswer: 'last',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'intermediate',
    instructions: 'Choose the answer that best represents the meaning of the sentence.',
    question: 'He may have got delayed.',
    options: [
      'He will arrive shortly.',
      'He has permission to arrive late.',
      'It is probable that he has been delayed.',
      'He was delayed.',
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'It is probable that he has been delayed.',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'intermediate',
    instructions: 'Select the best answer to complete the sentence.',
    question: 'The students, ___________, did extremely well in today’s English exam.',
    options: [
      'most of them have studied hard',
      'most of whom are study hard',
      'most of they had studied hard',
      'most of whom had studied hard',
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'most of whom had studied hard',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'intermediate',
    instructions: 'Select the best answer to complete the sentence.',
    question: 'The Wilsons had three children , ___________.',
    options: [
      'and both of them are musicians',
      'who all became musicians',
      'two musicians and one is a doctor',
      'all whom became musicians',
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'who all became musicians',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'intermediate',
    instructions: 'Select the best answer to complete the sentence.',
    question: 'Every year, a _______________ automobile race is held in Indianapolis.',
    options: ['five-hundred-mile', 'five-hundred-miles', 'five-hundred mile', 'five hundred miles'],
    correctAnswer: 'five-hundred mile',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'intermediate',
    instructions: 'Select the choice which best completes the paragraph.',
    question:
      'Laws should not dictate where people can or cannot smoke. _____________ . It also unfairly restricts people’s freedom of choice. Therefore, the decision on when and where to smoke should be left to common sense.',
    options: [
      'Most smokers are in fact considerate and respectful people. They do not wish to harm others around them.',
      'This is an issue that arouses a lot of anger on the part of nonsmokers.',
      'There is no proof that smoking harms the health of nonsmokers.',
      'Banning smoking in public places and offices only causes loss of revenue and lowers productivity.',
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'Banning smoking in public places and offices only causes loss of revenue and lowers productivity.',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'intermediate',
    instructions: 'Select the choice which best completes the paragraph.',
    question:
      'Hardly a week goes by without some advance in technology that would have seemed incredible some 50 or so years ago. ________________ . The next 25 years will see as many advances as have been witnessed in the past 150.',
    options: [
      'These developments in technology are bound to have a dramatic effect on our lives.',
      'Yet we can expect the rate of change to accelerate rather than slow down within our lifetime.',
      'For instance, over the past 20 years computers have revolutionized our lives.',
      'Whether the future is one mass of unemployment or greater freedom and leisure will depend on how this change is managed.',
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'Yet we can expect the rate of change to accelerate rather than slow down within our lifetime.',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'intermediate',
    instructions: 'Select the choice which best completes the paragraph.',
    question:
      'Hungary, with a population of about ten million, lies between Czechoslovakia to the north and Yugoslavia to the south. Most of this country consists of an extremely fertile plain through which the River Danube flows. _________________________. In addition to grain, the plain produces potatoes, sugar, wine and livestock. In the past the majority of Hungarians were farmers. In recent years, however, progress has been made with industrialization. The new industries are derived mainly from agricultural production.',
    options: [
      'The plain occupies a large area.',
      'Here a great deal of grain is grown.',
      'Along the river there is fertile land.',
      'This region is very densely populated.',
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'Here a great deal of grain is grown.',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'advanced',
    instructions:
      'The following sentence is a topic sentence, which states the main point. Choose the IRRELEVANT sentence, which does not support the main point.',
    question: 'It is not difficult to see why young people of today are so keen on motorbikes.',
    options: [
      'Motorbikes are faster than other vehicles.',
      'Young people under 17 are not allowed to have motorbikes.',
      'You can take a passenger with you on the seat behind you.',
      'Motorbikes give people a feeling of independence.',
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'Young people under 17 are not allowed to have motorbikes.',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'advanced',
    instructions:
      'The following sentence is a topic sentence, which states the main point. Choose the IRRELEVANT sentence, which does not support the main point.',
    question: 'We all should read more than we do.',
    options: [
      'Books can teach us how other people think and help us understand one another better.',
      'Television has, unfortunately, caused people to read less.',
      'Books help us understand not only other people but also ourselves.',
      'It is in books that we can find out about our past mistakes and triumphs so that we may learn from them.',
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'Television has, unfortunately, caused people to read less.',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'advanced',
    instructions:
      'The following sentence is a topic sentence, which states the main point. Choose the IRRELEVANT sentence, which does not support the main point.',
    question: 'Starting your own business requires many skills and resources.',
    options: [
      'You should know how to deal with your customers.',
      'You need enough money to cover the initial costs.',
      'You can be your own boss if you own a business.',
      'Bookkeeping and management ability are essential.',
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'You can be your own boss if you own a business.',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'advanced',
    instructions: 'Select the best TOPIC SENTENCE for the paragraph below.',
    question:
      '__________________________________. It is an animal about the size of a small cow. The people of Tibet use it to carry large and small loads. They drink its milk, eat its meat for food and weave its fur into cloth.',
    options: [
      'Tibetan people depend upon the yak in several ways.',
      'Tibet is famous for its animals.',
      'The yak is an important means of transportation in Tibet.',
      'The yak is adapted to the climate of Tibet.',
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'Tibetan people depend upon the yak in several ways.',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'advanced',
    instructions: 'Select the best TOPIC SENTENCE for the paragraph below.',
    question:
      '________________________________. Airlines depend on good weather conditions to keep their planes in the air. Workmen who construct buildings can work only in good weather. Farmers depend on sunshine and rain for growing crops. Merchants find that weather affects their business, for when the weather is bad people do not go shopping.',
    options: [
      'We should listen to a weather report everyday.',
      'Scientists are studying ways to control the weather.',
      'Weather is important to a great many people.',
      'Unfavorable weather conditions may affect air travel.',
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'Weather is important to a great many people.',
  },
  {
    difficulty: 'advanced',
    instructions: 'Select the best TOPIC SENTENCE for the paragraph below.',
    question:
      '________________________________. It is a very important part of the body. It is the organ that pumps blood through the body. It is a muscle that works all the time, even when you are asleep.',
    options: [
      'The heart is a very important organ.',
      'The heart is a muscle.',
      'The heart pumps blood through the body.',
      'The heart works all the time.',
    ],
    correctAnswer: 'The heart is a very important organ.',
  },
];
